Guide to the Henry Raup Wagner Collection of Texas and Coahuila Land Grants
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Henry Raup Wagner collection of Texas and Coahuila land grants
1829-1831
WA MSS S-341
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.5
(1 box)
Petitions for land grants in Coahuila and Texas and supporting documentation.
Wagner, Henry R. (Henry Raup), 1862-1957
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Henry Raup Wagner, 1919.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Other portions of Wagner's Texas manuscripts collection have been cataloged separately. They include papers of Jean Louis Berlandier and Philip Nolan.
Scope and Contents
The Henry Raup Wagner Collection of Texas and Coahuila Land Grants, contains petitions for land grants in Texas from the period 1829-31, including supporting documents and official endorsements from the period showing the disposition of the petitions. Many of the petitions are accompanied by testimony from Stephen F. Austin. The documents are arranged chronologically.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Land grants -- Mexico -- Coahuila and Texas; Land grants -- Texas; Coahuila and Texas (Mexico) -- History; Texas -- History -- To 1846; Public officers -- Mexico; Austin, Stephen F. (Stephen Fuller), 1793-1836; Pineda, Jose; Coahuila and Texas (Mexico). Governor (1827-1830: Viesca; Coahuila and Texas (Mexico). Governor (1831-1832: Letona)
- Nixon, George Anthony
  - Petition to land commissioner, Bexar, Texas, 1829 Oct 6 (Box 1, Folder +)
    Scope and Contents
    9 p. 31 cm. Accompanied by testimony of J.A. Padilla, grant by Gov. Viesca, and appointment of Francisco Madero as land commissioner by Governor Letona.
- Campos, Juan Vicente
  - Petition for 11 sitios of land, Leona Vicario, Mexico, 1830 Feb 24 (Box 1, Folder +)
    11 p. 32 cm.
- Harrison, Henry
  - Petition to General Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas, 1830 Mar 20 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by the testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official grant by the Governor of the State of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional land.
- Peebles, Robert, b.1798
  - Petition to General Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Mar 25 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Austin and the formal land grant of the governor of state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional land in Austin's colony.
- Williams, Samuel May, 1795-1858
  - Petition to General Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Apr 6 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of J. Antonio Padilla and Ramon Musquiz, and official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional sitios of land.
- Burnham, Jesse, 1792-1883
  - Petition to General Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Apr 26 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30.5 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for an additional sitio of land.
- Carbajal, José Luis
  - Petition to el Gefe Politico, Bexar, Texas., 1830 May 11 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 33 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Miguel Arciniega and Ygnacio Arocha for Ayuntamiento and official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for 2 sitios of land.
- Davenport, Juan Bernardo Benigno
  - Petition to the Governor, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 May 16 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by: testimony of Vicente Cordova and Luis Procela of the Ayuntamiento and official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas.
- Farias, José Antonio
  - Petition to Gefe Politico de este Departamento, Bexar, Texas., 1830 Jun 28 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 31 cm. Accompanied by orders signed by Ayuntamiento de Bexar and official grant of governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Gomez, José
  - Petition to Gefe Politico del Departamento de Bexar, Bexar, Texas., 1830 Jul 23 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 31.5 cm. Signed: José Gomez and Ygnacio de Leon. Accompanied by orders signed by Ayuntamiento de Bexar and official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Amero y Ruiz, José
  - Petition to Gobernador del Estado de Coahuila and Texas, New York., 1830 Aug 1 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 32 cm. Accompanied by official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for 11 sitios of land.
- Acosta, José Maríano
  - Petition to Gobernador del Estado, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Aug 2 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official grant of governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional land.
- Pineda, José
  - Petition to the Gobernador del Estado, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Aug 3 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by the official land grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional land for Maríano Mora.
- Gates, John
  - Petition to Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Aug 13 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Mora, Juan
  - Petition to El Gobernador, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Aug 17 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for 11 sitios of land.
- Barnett, Thomas, 1798-1843
  - Petition to Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Aug 24 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 31 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin, and official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for an additional sitio of land.
- Martin, Wyly, 1776-1842
  - Petition to commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Aug 26 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 31.5 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and the formal land grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional land.
- Pettus, John Freeman, 1808-1878
  - Petition to land commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Aug 27 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30.5 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Flores, Vital, 1790-1870
  - Petition to Gobernador del Estado, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Aug 30 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 27.5 cm. Accompanied by official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for 11 sitios of land.
- Pineda, José
  - Petition to Gobernador del Estado, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Aug 30 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas.
- Ybanda, Ygnacio
  - Petition to the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Aug 30 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Zaragoza, Miguel
  - Petition to Gobernador del Estado, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Aug 31 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by the document of the sale signed by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for eleven sitios of land.
- Mora, José María
  - Petition to Gobernador del Estado, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Sep 14 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for 9 sitios of land.
- Carbajal, José María Jesus, d.1874
  - Petition to Gefe politico de este departamento, San Fernando de Bejar, Texas., 1830 Sep 18 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 33 cm. Accompanied by report of the Ayuntamiento and official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for four sitios of land.
- Acosta, Juan José
  - Petition to Gobernador del Estado, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Sep 28 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant by governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for eleven sitios of land.
- Sanches, Simon
  - Petition to commissioner, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Sep 28 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Vince, Robert, d.1837
  - Petition to governor of Coahuila and Texas, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Oct 26 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Thomas Barnett and Samuel Williams and official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Barnett, William
  - Petition to governor of Coahuila and Texas, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Nov 6 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30.5 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and the official grant of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional land.
- Galindo, José Ignacio
  - Petition to the Gobernador of the state of Coahuila and Texas, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Nov 9 (Box 1, Folder +)
    13 p. map. 30 cm. Accompanied by copies of documents concerning the grant and the official grant by the governor. Request for 11 sitios of land.
- Gates, Samuel, d.1836
  - Petition to governor of Coahuila and Texas, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Nov 10 (Box 1, Folder +)
- Moreno, José María
  - Petition to Gobernador de Coahuila and Texas, Mexico., 1830 Nov 12 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 31 cm. Accompanied by official land grant by governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Ocampo, Carlos
  - Petition to commissioner, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1830 Nov 13 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by the official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Deel, Sarah
  - Petition to governor of Coahuila and Texas, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Nov 18 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land in Austin's colony.
- Harris, William Plunkett, 1797-1843
  - Petition to Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Nov 19 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional land.
- Hall, John W., ca.1786-1845
  - Petition to governor of Coahuila and Texas, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Nov 25 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by endorsement of Ayuntamiento and grant by Governor Viesca. Request for land.
- Leakey, Joel
  - Petition to governor of Coahuila and Texas, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Nov 27 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by the testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and the official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Kerr, James, 1790-1850
  - Petition to commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Dec 1 (Box 1, Folder +)
    5 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by the testimony of Thomas Barnett and Samuel Williams of the Ayuntamiento and official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Peebles, Robert, b.1798
  - Petition to General Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Dec 1 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by the official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Requests land for Marcelino Martinez.
- Philips, Zeno
  - Petition to commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Dec 1 (Box 1, Folder +)
- Scott, John H.
  - Petition to Commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Dec 1 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official land grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for a sitio of land.
- Grayson, Peter William, 1788-1838
  - Petition to commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Dec 2 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and official land grant by the governor of the states of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Moseley, Socrates S.
  - Petition to commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Dec 3 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by the testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and the official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Cartwright, Jesse H, b. ca.1787
  - Petition to commissioner, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Dec 8 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 31 cm. Accompanied by the testimony of Stephen Fuller Austin and grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for additional land.
- Clements, Joséph D.
  - Petition, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1830 Dec 21 (Box 1, Folder +)
    5 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by testimony of Thomas Barnett and Samuel Williams for Ayuntamiento and the official grant by the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for 5 sitios of land.
- Gallard, Juan José
  - Petition, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1831 Jan 4 (Box 1, Folder +)
    2 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant of the governor of Coahuila and Texas. Request for 11 sitios of land.
- Ruiz de Esparza, Andre
  - Petition, Monterrey, Mexico., 1831 Jan 4 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 31.5 cm. Accompanied by official grant of the governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas. Request for 11 sitios of land.
- Cruz, Valentin
  - Petition to Gobernador of Coahuila and Texas, Leona Vicario, Mexico., 1831 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant of the governor of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Scott, George W.
  - Petition, Villa de Austin, Texas., 1831 Jan 22 (Box 1, Folder +)
    5 p. 30 cm. Signed: George W. Scott and William H. Scott. Accompanied by the official land grant of the Governor and the testimony of Stephen F. Austin. Request for land.
- Muldoon, Michael
  - Petition for land grant, Leona Vicario, Mexico., 1831 Feb 4 (Box 1, Folder +)
    4 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant by the governor of Coahuila and Texas.
- Garza, Joaquin de la
  - Petition to the Gefe politico de este departamento, Bejar, Texas., 1831 Feb 9 (Box 1, Folder +)
    6 p. 31 cm. Accompanied by testimony of José María Salinas for Ayuntamiento and official grant by the governor of Coahuila and Texas.
- Gil, Carlos
  - Petition to Gobernador del estado, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1831 Feb 10 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant by the governor of Coahuila and Texas.
- Elguezabal, José Valentin
  - Petition, Nacogdoches, Texas., 1831 Feb 27 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant of the governor of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land.
- Aguirre, José María
  - Petition to the Gobernador of Coahuila and Texas, Leona Vicario, Mexico., 1831 Oct 7 (Box 1, Folder +)
    3 p. 30 cm. Accompanied by official grant of the governor of Coahuila and Texas. Request for land for José María del Castillo.